Guide to the Robert J. Havighurst Papers 1921-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series VIII: Chicago Schools
  - School Board, 1979 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Legal Developments, 1979 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Pairing Clusters-LA (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Multi-District Plan for Desegregation (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - LA Spencer Report, 1977-1978 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Monitoring Committee (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Independent Analysis Unit, Los Angeles Board of Education (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Education and Society in Chicago (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - The Black Community and the Public School System (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Book Review: Invisible Children, School Integration (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Race and Class of Urban Teachers (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - KIRP Richmond (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Chicago Board of Education (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Test Data (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Schools Test Data, 73-74 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Confusion About Middle Age (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Critics and Education (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Misspending Money: March 16-April 25, 1972 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Redmond Issue, 1975 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Summer of 1975 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Bussing Study (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - R. Piedra to RJH (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - 20 Top Area High Schools in Chicago-1979 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Access to Excellence (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Equalizing Educational Opportunities in the New Chicago (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Education and Society in Chicago (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - 1980 School Program-Finance (Box 95, Folder 10)
- Series IX: Illinois Education
  - The Welfare and Health Systems and the Chicago School System (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - The Effect of Public School Expenditures on House Values (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - High Schools Letters (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - Milwaukee Schools and Segregation (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Schools Data (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Quality of Ed (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-Other Cities (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Integration (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Demography and Schools (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Chi-SMH-High Ed (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Census Tract Data (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Chi Ser Schools (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Special Education in Chicago Area (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Report to RJH Submitted by Thomas Moorefield, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Merit Semi Finalists (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - McCaul-History (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Stephen Hazlett (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Learning and Teaching (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - School and Suburbs (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Chicago Data (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Ratios-Pop to Students (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Racial Headcount (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Demographic Material (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - SER-Enrollments to Rations-Raw (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Pop-U enrollment (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Demographic Data-Chicago Test Area (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Youth in the City (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Demographic Data-Chicago Negro Density Percentages by Districts (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence re: Regional High School Plan (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - School Survey District Organization (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Demographic Data: Integration and Open Attendance (Baltimore, Chicago, Detroit) (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Extra Pages (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Map of Chicago SMSA (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - DOLL Test Data on Typical Schools (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - Suburban School Systems: O’Shea and Havighurst (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - Teachers (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - Pupil Personnel Services (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Joint Committee on Public School Affairs (Box 97, Folder 19)
  - North Central Association (Box 97, Folder 20)
  - Citizens Schools Committee (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Civic Federation-Business and Education (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Board of Education (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Public School Fight, 1946-1947 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Church and Schools Shared Time and Released Time (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Statement to the Chicago Region of the Illinois Congress of Parents and Teachers, February 11, 1965 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Willis Ads, 1965-1966 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Article on School Survey (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - You and Your Schools-RJH, Address to Men’s Club of Sinai, 5-26-65 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Excerpts from Address to City Club on the Survey of the Chicago Public School, Nov 16, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - "Hauser and Havighurst: Two Reports on a Shelf," Chicago Sun-Times, Oct 31 1965 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - School Survey, Speeches by RJH (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Public Schools, 1948-1960 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Introduction (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Survey Report-Publications (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Printing of Report (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Survey Committee (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Willis (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Meetings of Survey Committee (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Finances of Survey (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Budget Survey (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Whiston (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Staff (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Progress Reports (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Lehne Current (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Tables (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Grace and Willis Correspondence (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, bdg. Ed. (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Survey General Correspondence (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Suggestions for Survey (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Survey Correspondence Organizations (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Survey Background (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Von Humboldt School-Fawell (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - Survey Correspondence Volunteer Offers (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - School Survey-Libraries (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - School Survey-Television (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Committee on Adult Education (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Volunteer Projects (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Remedial Reading Program (Volunteer Work Project) (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - High Schools (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Demographic Data-Chicago-Bowen High School (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Some Observations Concerning Chicago High Schools (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Secondary Schools-Types (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Secondary Schools-Visits (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Consultant Reports (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Curricular Contests (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Junior Colleges (Box 101, Folder 12)
  - School Survey-Teachers College (Box 101, Folder 13)
  - School Survey-Higher Education (Box 101, Folder 14)
  - School Survey- Correspondence, general (Box 101, Folder 15)
  - School Survey-Libraries (Box 101, Folder 16)
  - School Survey-Higher Ed (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Charts of Institutional Characteristics (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Thomas E. Moorefield-Reports (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Russell Doll-Final Report (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Community Study (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - The Anderson Community (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Survey Report (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Peoples’ PTA (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Ray PTA (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Mulberry Address (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Contacts (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Metro Data (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Round Table on Southeast Commission (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - The Integrated Urban Local Community (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - Hyde Park Survey-1948 (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - Hyde Park Centennial (Box 102, Folder 16)
  - Comm. Renewal (Box 102, Folder 17)
  - Chicago Segregation Issues-Survey Matters, 1967-1970 (Box 102, Folder 18)
  - Hancock, Margaret Campbell (Box 102, Folder 19)
  - Chicago-Race Relations Study (Box 102, Folder 20)
  - Master Copy-Final Report-Society and Education in Chicago (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Chi in Black Community (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Population (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - ‘Reverend Jesse L. Jackson and the Push Program for Excellence in Big City Schools,’ Aug 1976 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Black Community (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - Population (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Project Wingspread (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Southwest Side Community (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - USOE Group (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Population and the Development of Educational Systems in the Chicago Area (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Chi H/S (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - The Catholic Schools, Sanders (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Willis and Redmond (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - Ed in Chicago, general (Box 103, Folder 14)
  - Revisions (Box 103, Folder 15)
  - Citizens School Committee (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - ND NPOR Reserve (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Society and Education (1 of 2) (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Society and Education (2 of 2) (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Melling (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Joseph P. Handon (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - School Visits (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Schools Research (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Background Material-Chicago before 1977 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Chicago Schools (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - SC-Rubin-School Desegregation (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Hannon Resignation (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Absent 1981 Plan (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - HEW Deseg Plan (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - August 1981 Plan (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - ILL Board of Ed (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - August 1981 Desegregation Plan (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Racial/Ethnic Survey-Students (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - Gary Orfield (Box 105, Folder 15)
  - School Board Deseg (Box 105, Folder 16)
  - State Board Tech Community Report, Orfield, May 1978 (Box 105, Folder 17)
  - Integrated Education: Weinberg (Box 105, Folder 18)
  - Teachers and other Organizations (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Educational Needs (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Desegregation Betm 1965 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Desegregation (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Block studies (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Education in Large Cities (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Schools in Chicago (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - Teacher Integration (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Desegregation (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Urban Education (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Interviews re: Schools, 1979 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - J. Jackson (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Transparencies (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - The Business System and the School System, II.3 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Chronology (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Chicago Schools (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers and Chicago Schools (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Early History (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Hannon (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Oak Park (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Suburbs (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Desegregation of Chicago Schools (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - WJ Brogan (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - A Historical Sketch to 1925 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - Herrick-The Financial Collapse of the Chicago Schools in 1929 (Box 107, Folder 12)
  - Superintendents (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - William H. Johnson, Supt. Chicago Schools, 1936-1946 (Box 107, Folder 14)
  - McAndrew (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Willis (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Desegregation Material (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Chicago SMSA (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Demographic Data-Chicago Clustering of Schools (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Official Report of the Proceedings of the Board of Education, Hauser Report (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - B756 #738 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - 746 #688 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - 698 #676 (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - School Board and Teachers’ Strike (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Population Projections (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - School Reform Funding (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - Background (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Monitoring Commission (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Integration Honor Roll (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Largest Central City Districts (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - Chicago School Politics (Box 108, Folder 17)
  - Gary Orfield (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Teachers Organizations Extra Stuff (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - CIECE (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Central Cities (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - CWAC 1978 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Transparencies (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Catholic Schools (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Cities Under Stress (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Educational Problems of the Big Cities (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - The University of Chicago, Parts I-3 (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - The Hard To Reach Adolescent (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Special Policy Issues in Management of Student Aid (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - 1975 First National Conference on Urban Education (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - Role and Responsibilities for Commission for Desegregation Implementation (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - Public Schools in Big-City Redevelopment (Box 109, Folder 15)
  - Interim Report-A Promise of Simple Justice (Box 109, Folder 16)
  - Plan for the Implementation of the Promises of Title VI (Box 109, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 109, Folder 18)
  - Board of Ed Search Committee, 1975 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Hispanic-Bilingual (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Latino School Policy (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Bilingual (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Alternative Schools Network (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Chicago Schools Decentralization (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - PWT Reserve (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Higher Ed in Chicago (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - CWAC 1980 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Schools (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Schools-good (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Public Schools-Race/Ethnic Data (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - LA Schools (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - LA Schools, Extra Copies (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Los Angeles Correspondence (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Spring 1981 Closed Mandatory Bussing (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - LA USD Plan Spring 1977 (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Integrated Educational Excellence (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Desegregation of the Public Schools of LA Report (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - 1977-1978 Spencer Correspondence (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Spencer, 1980 (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - Spencer Fund, Expenses, 1978-1981 (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Spencer Business Reports after 1981 (Box 111, Folder 14)
  - Spencer 1982 (Box 111, Folder 15)
  - IV, V, and VI (Box 111, Folder 16)
  - Spencer Foundation., 1978-1979 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Spencer, 1982-1983 (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Opportunities for Higher Education (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Integration in LA 25 Years and Beyond (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Roberta Piedra (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Spencer Reserve (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Current AE (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - School Visits (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Marco A. Martinez (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Lerner (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Celia Hunt (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Bdg. Ed, Miscellaneous (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - Benton Fund Proposals, 1981 (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - McCane-RMA-Spencer Report, August 1983 (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - LA and Chicago Schools, Spencer Foundation (Box 112, Folder 15)
  - Blacks (Box 112, Folder 16)
  - Desegregation Study (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - Effective Schools (Box 112, Folder 18)
  - Interviews with Rice (Box 112, Folder 19)
  - Spencer Foundation Reports (Box 112, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 112, Folder 21)
  - Analysis of Chicago’s Progress (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Cheng-Miscellaneous Nastasia (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Desegregation Materials (1 of 2) (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Desegregation Materials (2 of 2) (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Courts and Desegregation (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Economic Problems of Blacks in Chicago (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - ICEE Ethnicity in Education (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Chicago ESAA Projects (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - Report to Spencer Foundation, 1981 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - CWAC and Access to Excellence (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Education Reports (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - RJH for McCaul (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - California State Board of Ed Decision (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Desegregation Timelines (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - LA Clippings (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - M. Price Reports (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Feasibility of a Metropolitan Plan to Comply with Crawford v. Board of Ed, 1977 (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - United Teachers of LA (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - NIE Request (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Background on LA-Chi Research (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Crawford v. Board of Ed., 1979 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - RJH Notes on LA (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - CASCI-Los Angeles-Chicago (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - LA Clippings (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - RJH, LA, 1984 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - March-April 1979 Reserve (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Staff Report to the Board of Directors, Council for Peace and Equity in Education (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - Farley (Box 115, Folder 10)
  - LA Clippings, Autumn 1978 (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - Morgan Park High School (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Vernon Dist. 18 MLAC, Preschool, David (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - La Salle School Language Center, Dist #7, Marco (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Juarez HS, District 19 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Tuley Middle, Marco, Dist #6 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - Clemente High, Marco, District 6 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - Howe Performing Arts, District 4 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - Burbank Basic Skills (Box 116, Folder 8)
  - Dirksen, Basic Skills, Dist #1, Marco (Box 116, Folder 9)
  - Summer School Brochures, 1975 (Box 116, Folder 10)
  - Hess U. of C., Business Ed, Computer Ed, Consumer Ed, District 19 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - Ray School District Program, Bowie (Box 116, Folder 12)
  - Reavis, K-5 (Box 116, Folder 13)
  - Lawless UGC District Related Programs (Box 116, Folder 14)
  - Charles Kozminski School, Basic Skills Center (Box 116, Folder 15)
  - Piedra (Box 116, Folder 16)
  - Bowen HS (Box 116, Folder 17)
  - Phillip Sheridan Bilingual, Roberta (Box 116, Folder 18)
  - Thorpe K-8 (Box 116, Folder 19)
  - 6.85 (Box 116, Folder 20)
  - Board of Education Meetings (Box 116, Folder 21)
  - CWAC, Feb 14-March 21 (Box 116, Folder 22)
  - Interview with D. Moore, District 18 (Box 116, Folder 23)
  - Chissold District 18, Extensive Studies (Basic Skills) (Box 116, Folder 24)
  - Gage Park H.S., District 12 (Box 116, Folder 25)
  - Curie Lerner (Box 116, Folder 26)
  - Curie HS, District 12 (Box 116, Folder 27)
  - Kenwood Academy, District 16 (Box 116, Folder 28)
  - Higgins K-8 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Marta Alvorado (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Bret Harte School (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - David’s Odds and Ends (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Liberal Education (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Functions of Universities (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Staff Paper-New York Education (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Minneapolis (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Materials on RJH Study of Colleges and Universities (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Impact of Population Change (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Who Should Go to College? (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - How Many to College? (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - College and Talent (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Talented College Students (Box 117, Folder 14)
  - Coll Enrollment Predictions (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Enrollment-Sec. (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Deschooling (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - School Issues, Miscellaneous (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Analysis Urban Study (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - What is Right with Education (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Criticism from Within (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Attacks on Education (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Teachers (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Controlling Faculty Size (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Introduction-The Structure of the Academic Professions (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - Institutional Cooperation (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Occupational Mobility and Higher Education (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Kansas City (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - HRC Staff (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Mrs. Wimsatt (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Magnet Schools in LA (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - International Education (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Evaluation (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - LA Aug 1977 Visit (Box 119, Folder 9)
  - Los Angeles Apex (Box 119, Folder 10)
  - Praeger Book (Box 119, Folder 11)
  - CWAC Material (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Brazil Employees Questionnaire (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - PDK Computer (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - CWAC II, Autumn-Winter 1978-1979 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - CWAC Spring-Summer 1978 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Position Papers (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Welling October 27-Nov 2 (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Position Papers 1-45 (Box 120, Folder 8)
  - Plan Components (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Racial Ethnic Data (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Head Count Data (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Demographic Data: Chicago Head Count (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - 1970-1975 Chicago Schools (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - 1975-76 on Book (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - The Press and the Schools (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - School Board, 1978 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Design for the Future (Box 121, Folder 9)
  - Education and Society in Chicago (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - CWAC Meeting, 1977-1978 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Schools, 1970 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Access to Excellence Papers, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Chicago Forum, 1972, Urban Ed (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Redmond Rehiring, Dec 28, 1974-April 27, 1975 (1-2) (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - 3 Newspapers, Summer of 1975 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Redmond Rehiring, March 26-May 29, 1974 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Misspending Money, Daily News, July 1 1971-July 30, 1972 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - CWAC (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - Desegregation and Chicago Public Schools (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - RM Notes, CWAC, 1977 (Box 122, Folder 12)
  - Progress Report and Proposed Educational Opportunities Plan (Box 122, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, CWAC (Box 122, Folder 14)
  - CWAC Report, 1978 (Box 122, Folder 15)
  - CWAC Spring 1979-Summer (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - Dec 9-16 Plan (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - CIWAC Notes (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - Rosen San Diego Minority Isolated Schools (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - Computer Assistance for School Desegregation (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - Equalizing Educational Opportunities for the New Chicago, Sept 1977 (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - Adv. Committee (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - Center to Wellness Education (Box 123, Folder 8)
- Series X: Cross-Cultural and International Studies
  - Subseries 1: American Indian Education
    - Illinois Ed. (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Ill. St. Dept. (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - Min. Competency (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - Early Retirement of Teachers, Illinois Board of Education (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - Illinois State Board of Education Research and Evaluation Adv. Council (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - Low-Class Subcultures in the Big City (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - Fyans Test Anxiety (Box 123, Folder 15)
    - Research and Evaluation Committee, Illinois State Board of Ed. (Box 123, Folder 16)
    - Ch 12 Part III Intro (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - REAC (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - James Coleman Class of 1982 Research (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Southern Illinois University Job Stress Study (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - First Six Years (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Urban Indians, Am Indian Policy Review, 1977 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - Kappan, American Indians, 1982 (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Alienation-Spilka (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - Introduction to Indian Education (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Education of Indian Children and Youth (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - The Analysis of Interview and Questionnaire (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Attitudes and Ratings (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Self-Concept (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Mental Health (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - SD Data (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Self-Concept (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - L’Ecuyer Self-Concept (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Washington Indian Conference (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Indian Study Conference (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Oak Park Conference (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - Indian Self-Concept (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - Indian Mental Health-Suicide (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - Indian Project-Plans for Research, 1941-1944 (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - Native American Children Educational Achievement (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Current Indian Paper (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Urban Indian Dialogue (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - National Study of Indian Education (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Influential Persons-Distribution of Ratin, Eric (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Problems of Evaluating Indian Education (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Fed Government and Indian Affairs (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Congressman (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Outline of Final Report and Recommendations (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - NSAIE-Memo to Adv. CTTE and Field Centers, Dated September 28, 1970 (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - A Privately Financed Commission on Indian Education (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - NSAIE Responsibility of Federal Government for Education of Indian Youth (Box 126, Folder 11)
    - Goals for Indian Education (Box 126, Folder 12)